Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine and we're on the road today.
我是Catherine，今天我们正在旅途中。
We're traveling a little bit.
我们稍微旅行了一下。
That's right.
没错。
Today we have a lesson that was requested by one of our users and I think it's a very
今天我们有一节课是由一位用户请求的，我觉得这课非常
handy lesson.
实用。
If we're traveling, we are buying tickets at a train station.
如果我们正在旅行，我们在火车站买票。
That's right.
没错。
So I personally love traveling by train.
我个人很喜欢坐火车旅行。
I think it's a very romantic way to see different countries, different places.
我觉得这是一种很浪漫的方式来看不同的国家、不同的地方。
We're going to learn all about how to get tickets and how to talk about different parts
我们将学习如何买票以及如何谈论火车的不同部分
of a train.
的词汇。
So let's first listen to our dialogue.
那么我们先来听一下对话。
Hi, I would like to purchase a one-way ticket to Brussels, please.
你好，我想买一张去布鲁塞尔的单程票。
Certainly, sir.
好的，先生。
This is our train schedule.
这是我们的列车时刻表。
We have an express train departing every morning and an overnight train that departs at 9 p.m.
我们有一趟每天早上出发的快速列车和一趟晚上9点出发的夜间列车。
How long does it take to get there?
到那里需要多长时间？
About 12 hours.
大约12小时。
We currently have tickets available only for first class on the express train.
目前快速列车只有头等舱的票了。
If you'd like, you can choose a sleeper on the overnight train, which is a bit less expensive.
如果您愿意，可以选择夜间列车的卧铺，价格稍微便宜一些。
Yeah, I think that's the best option.
是的，我觉得这是最好的选择。
Do you serve food on a train?
火车上提供食物吗？
12 hours is such a long time.
12小时太长了。
Yes, of course.
当然提供。
There is a dining car towards the end of the train where they serve meals at all times.
在列车尾部有一节餐车，全天供应餐食。
We do provide complimentary water and coffee for all of our passengers.
我们为所有乘客免费提供水和咖啡。
Great.
太好了。
I'll take it.
我就要这个了。
Here you are, sir.
给您，先生。
Your train leaves from platform number 9 at 9 on the dot.
您的列车从9号站台准时9点出发。
Remember to be here at least 30 minutes before your scheduled departure time or else you
请记得至少在预定出发时间前30分钟到达，否则您
might miss your train.
可能会错过火车。
I understand.
我明白了。
Thank you very much.
非常感谢。
Have a great trip.
祝您旅途愉快。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So now we're going to take a look at a couple of words that we've picked out for you on
现在我们要来看一下我们为你们挑选的几个单词，在
Language Takeaway.
“语言要点”部分。
“语言要点”。
So there are many different kinds of tickets you can purchase, you can buy for your train
所以你可以购买很多不同类型的火车票
journey.
用于你的火车旅行。
The first time we're going to talk about is maybe the fastest.
我们要谈的第一种可能是最快的。
This is called an express train.
这叫做快速列车。
That's right.
没错。
So as the name says, it's an express train.
就像名字说的，它是快速列车。
That means it's a very fast train.
意思是它是一列非常快的火车。
And it depends because in different places, sometimes they call it the fast train, sometimes
这取决于不同地方，有时他们叫它快车，有时
they call it the express train.
叫它快速列车。
But basically the idea is that it's a very fast train.
但基本上意思就是它是一列非常快的火车。
And it's fast usually because it stops very few times.
它通常很快是因为它停靠站很少。
For example, if we want to go on the Paris to Berlin train, it won't stop in every single
比如，如果我们想坐从巴黎到柏林的火车，它不会在每个
town.
小镇都停。
It will probably only stop a couple of times.
它可能只停靠几次。
Exactly.
没错。
So apart from the express trains that usually they'll go in the daytime, we have an overnight
所以除了通常在白天运行的快速列车，我们还有夜间
train.
列车。
Overnight trains are very fun, or at least they can be fun if you have a comfortable
夜间列车很有趣，或者至少如果你有一个舒适的
place to sleep.
地方睡觉，它们会很有趣。
Basically the idea is you get on the train at night and you sleep on the train and you
基本上就是晚上上车，在火车上睡觉，然后
get off in the morning.
早上到站下车。
That's right.
没错。
It's actually a very popular way of traveling, especially if you're on a budget because you're
这其实是一种很受欢迎的旅行方式，特别是如果你预算有限，因为你
basically saving yourself one night of spending the night at a hotel.
基本上省了一晚住酒店的钱。
That's right.
没错。
So you're going to have to find a place to sleep if you're taking the overnight train.
所以如果你坐夜间列车，你需要找个地方睡觉。
There are usually different options.
通常有不同的选择。
The most uncomfortable is usually a seat, like a hard seat.
最不舒服的通常是座位，比如硬座。
But there are oftentimes special cars on a train where you can sleep for these overnight
但火车上通常有专门的车厢，供这些夜间
trips.
旅行时睡觉用。
What are those called?
那些叫什么？
That's right.
没错。
And those are called sleeper cars or you choose a sleeper seat.
那些叫做卧铺车厢，或者你可以选择卧铺座位。
Right.
对。
So that's pretty easy to remember.
这很容易记住。
So you choose a sleep sleeper.
所以你选择卧铺。
The sleeper seats are the seats that fold back like you're lying down.
卧铺座位是可以折叠起来像躺下一样的座位。
But of course most places like China and India and Vietnam for example have actual cars that
但当然，像中国、印度和越南等很多地方，有实际的车厢
have beds in them.
里面放着床。
Right, right.
对，对。
Yeah.
是的。
So you can, as the name says, you can actually sleep on this train.
所以，顾名思义，你实际上可以在这列火车上睡觉。
Now if you're going to buy tickets, you're not going to find a sleeper train on an express
如果你要买票，你不会在快车上找到卧铺列车，
train or a train that travels during the day.
或者白天行驶的火车。
These are only available at night usually.
这些通常只在夜间才有。
That's right.
没错。
So a sleeper car is what you want to look for if you're traveling overnight.
所以，如果你要夜间旅行，卧铺车厢就是你要找的。
And in those cases, you oftentimes get hungry.
在这种情况下，你经常会感到饿。
You need to eat.
你需要吃东西。
So where do you go to eat?
那你去哪里吃呢？
That's right.
没错。
We're going to look for the dining car on the train.
我们要找火车上的餐车。
Okay.
好的。
So think about the word dining room.
想想“餐厅”这个词。
Dining room, dining car, this means the place where you eat.
餐厅、餐车，意思就是吃饭的地方。
That's right.
没错。
So we're going to look for a dining car and it's usually in the front of the train I think
所以我们要找餐车，我想它通常在火车的前部，
and you can just go and get a quick meal over there.
你可以去那里快速吃顿饭。
That's right.
没错。
Dining car.
餐车。
And finally, we have another very important word here.
最后，这里还有一个非常重要的词。
It's all about getting on and off the train.
这完全关于上下火车。
So where do you do that?
那你在哪里上下车呢？
Well, you go to the platform, the specific platform where your train is leaving.
嗯，你去站台，你的火车出发的那个特定站台。
So in this case, this guy has to go to platform number nine.
所以在这个例子中，这个人得去九号站台。
Okay.
好的。
So usually that means that there is a cement or a stone block where you stand.
所以通常那意味着有一个水泥或石头平台让你站着。
The train comes to the station.
火车进站。
People get off, you get on.
人们下车，你上车。
So the place where that all happens is the platform.
所以这一切发生的地方就是站台。
That's right.
没错。
And remember that in airplanes or in airports, usually you look for a terminal.
记住，在飞机或机场，你通常找航站楼。
For train stations, you're looking for a platform.
在火车站，你找的是站台。
All right.
好的。
And that number is going to be very important.
那个号码非常重要。
So look at your ticket and find out which platform your train will be arriving or departing
所以看看你的票，找出你的火车到达或出发的站台
from.
是哪个。
That's right.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
So now why don't we review these words.
那么现在我们来复习一下这些词。
Let's listen to the dialogue again and we'll be back in a bit.
让我们再听一遍对话，一会儿回来。
Hi, I would like to purchase a one-way ticket to Brussels, please.
你好，我想买一张去布鲁塞尔的单程票。
Certainly, sir.
好的，先生。
This is our train schedule.
这是我们的火车时刻表。
We have an express train departing every morning and an overnight train that departs at 9 p.m.
我们有一趟每天早上出发的快车，和一趟晚上9点出发的夜车。
How long does it take to get there?
到那里需要多长时间？
About 12 hours.
大约12小时。
We currently have tickets available only for first class on the express train.
目前我们只有快车的头等舱票。
If you'd like, you can choose a sleeper on the overnight train, which is a bit less expensive.
如果你愿意，你可以选择夜车上的卧铺，那会便宜一点。
Yeah, I think that's the best option.
是的，我觉得那是最好的选择。
Do you serve food on a train?
火车上提供食物吗？
12 hours is such a long time.
12小时太长了。
Yes, of course.
是的，当然。
There is a dining car towards the end of the train where they serve meals at all times.
火车尾部有一节餐车，随时提供餐食。
We do provide complimentary water and coffee for all of our passengers.
我们为所有乘客免费提供水和咖啡。
Great.
太好了。
I'll take it.
我买了。
Here you are, sir.
给您，先生。
Your train leaves from platform number 9 at 9 on the dot.
您的火车在9点整从9号站台出发。
Remember to be here at least 30 minutes before your scheduled departure time or else you
记得至少在预定出发时间前30分钟到这里，否则你
might miss your train.
可能会错过火车。
I understand.
我明白了。
Thank you very much.
非常感谢。
Have a great trip.
祝您旅途愉快。
Okay.
好的。
So we've got some really great phrases today on Fluency Builder, not that many of them
今天我们在流利度训练环节学到了一些很棒的短语，虽然不多，
but they're very useful.
但非常有用。
The first one is a kind of ticket you can buy.
第一个是一种你可以买的票。
That's right.
没错。
We're looking for a one-way ticket to Brussels.
我们要买一张去布鲁塞尔的单程票。
Okay.
好的。
So a one-way ticket means you go to Brussels but you don't come home.
所以单程票意味着你去布鲁塞尔，但不回家。
Maybe you have a flight later or you have a car waiting for you.
也许你之后有航班，或者有车在等你。
You don't need a return ticket on that train.
你不需要那趟火车的回程票。
One-way ticket is the opposite of a round-trip ticket.
单程票是往返票的反义词。
That's right.
没错。
So usually, for example, if you live in New York and you're going on vacation, you're
所以通常，比如，如果你住在纽约去度假，你会
going to buy a round-trip ticket because you need to go back to your city.
买往返票，因为你需要回你的城市。
But in this case, we're getting a one-way ticket.
但在这个例子中，我们买的是单程票。
So we're just buying a ticket that will only take us there.
所以我们只是买一张能带我们到那里的票。
It's not going to bring us back.
它不会带我们回来。
Okay.
好的。
One-way ticket.
单程票。
And after that, we have a good question.
之后，我们有一个好问题。
This is something we can ask in many, many different situations.
这是一个在很多很多不同场合都可以问的问题。
Here the person buying the ticket wants to know how long does it take to get there.
这里买票的人想知道到那里需要多长时间。
He's talking about Brussels.
他是在说布鲁塞尔。
That's right.
没错。
So let's take a look at this structure.
那我们来看看这个结构。
We can say how long does it take to and then we can add another verb there.
我们可以说“how long does it take to”，然后再加上另一个动词。
So for example, we want to know the amount of time it is going to require.
比如，我们想知道需要多少时间。
For example, here we are asking how long does it take to get there, in this case to Brussels.
例如，这里我们问的是到那里需要多长时间，这里指的是到布鲁塞尔。
We're asking how much time is needed to go to Brussels, but what if we change the last
我们问的是去布鲁塞尔需要多少时间，但如果我们改变最后
part?
一部分呢？
Well, there's anything.
嗯，什么都可以。
We could say anything here.
这里我们可以说任何东西。
We could say how long does it take to bake a pizza?
我们可以说烤一个披萨需要多长时间？
Or for example, Marco, how long does it take for you to do your hair in the morning?
或者，比如，马可，你早上弄头发需要多长时间？
Like 20 seconds.
大概20秒。
Not very long.
不太长。
You could even change the name of the place you're going to.
你甚至可以改变你要去的地方的名字。
So how long does it take to get to Beijing?
那么到北京需要多长时间？
Exactly, so just remember this structure when you want to ask the amount of time needed.
没错，所以当你问需要多少时间时，记住这个结构。
Of course, there are other ways and sometimes it's very common to make a little bit of mistakes
当然，还有其他方式，有时候人们很容易犯一些小错误，
saying how much time to Beijing or something like this.
比如说“how much time to Beijing”之类的。
Or how many hours.
或者“how many hours”。
We don't really say that in English.
英语里我们一般不这么说。
We say how much time.
我们说“how much time”。
So how much time does it take?
所以是“how much time does it take？”
All right.
好的。
And what about when the person that's selling the ticket said, okay, the train leaves from
那卖票的人说“好的，火车从九号站台九点整出发”呢？
platform number nine at nine on the dot?
Okay, so I'm not really sure where this idea of a dot comes from, but I think it has to
好的，我不太确定“dot”这个说法从哪来的，但我觉得和钟表有关。
do with clocks.
So basically when you look at a clock and all of a sudden the hand comes to 12, so it's
基本上，当你看着钟，突然指针指向12，那就是九点整，指针在12上，那就是“on the dot”。
nine o'clock, the hand is on the 12, that is on the dot.
That means exactly.
意思是“正好”。
Okay, so the train is leaving at nine zero zero, not nine 30, not nine 15.
好的，所以火车在九点整出发，不是九点半，也不是九点十五分。
It's leaving exactly at nine o'clock.
它正好在九点出发。
So we can also say this in normal speech when we're talking to our friends.
所以我们在和朋友聊天时也可以这么说。
I could say, Marco, we're going to leave at six on the dot.
我可以说，马可，我们六点整出发。
Any later and we'll miss the movie.
再晚就赶不上电影了。
Exactly.
没错。
But when you say on the dot, you're usually emphasizing that it leaves promptly.
但你说“on the dot”时，通常是在强调准时出发。
It's not going to be late and you're kind of emphasizing a person to be on time.
它不会晚点，而且你是在强调要某人准时。
Yes, please don't be late because, so nine oh one or in my case, six oh four, these are
是的，请不要迟到，因为九点零一分，或者对我来说六点零四分，这些都不行，因为太晚了。
not okay because they're too late.
Exactly.
没错。
So I'm going to pick you up at four o'clock on the dot.
所以我四点整来接你。
Usually means I don't really want to wait, so please be ready at four.
通常意味着我不想等，所以请四点准备好。
All right, so on the dot.
好的，所以是“on the dot”。
All right, so now let's listen to our dialogue for the last time and we'll be back to talk
好的，那现在我们最后听一遍对话，然后回来再聊一会儿。
with you a little bit more.
Hi, I would like to purchase a one-way ticket to Brussels, please.
你好，我想买一张去布鲁塞尔的单程票。
Certainly, sir.
好的，先生。
This is our train schedule.
这是我们的火车时刻表。
We have an express train departing every morning and an overnight train that departs at nine
我们有一趟每天早上出发的特快列车，和一趟晚上九点出发的夜班列车。
PM.
How long does it take to get there?
到那里需要多长时间？
About 12 hours.
大约12小时。
We currently have tickets available only for first class on the express train.
目前我们只有特快列车的一等座票。
If you'd like, you can choose a sleeper on the overnight train, which is a bit less expensive.
如果您愿意，可以选择夜班列车的卧铺，价格稍微便宜一些。
Yeah, I think that's the best option.
是的，我觉得那是最好的选择。
Do you serve food on a train?
火车上提供食物吗？
12 hours is such a long time.
12小时太长了。
Yes, of course.
是的，当然。
There is a dining car towards the end of the train where they serve meals at all times.
在火车尾部有一节餐车，随时提供餐食。
We do provide complimentary water and coffee for all of our passengers.
我们为所有乘客免费提供水和咖啡。
Great, I'll take it.
太好了，我就要这个。
Here you are, sir.
给您，先生。
Your train leaves from platform number nine at nine on the dot.
您的火车从九号站台九点整出发。
Remember to be here at least 30 minutes before your scheduled departure time or else you
请记得至少在预定出发时间前30分钟到达，否则
might miss your train.
您可能会错过火车。
I understand.
我明白了。
Thank you very much.
非常感谢。
Have a great trip.
祝您旅途愉快。
All right, so you mentioned you really like to travel on trains.
好的，你提到你很喜欢坐火车旅行。
I do.
是的。
Why is that?
为什么这么说？
Well, I like that trains are kind of slow.
嗯，我喜欢火车比较慢。
Many trains are slow.
很多火车都很慢。
Some trains, as we said, like express trains are faster.
有些火车，比如我们说的特快列车，会更快一些。
But if you're traveling in a new place, it's a wonderful way to see the country because
但如果你在一个新地方旅行，坐火车是欣赏沿途风景的好方式，因为
maybe you're going from one city to another city.
你可能是从一个城市到另一个城市。
Well, it's nice to see what's in between cities.
嗯，看看城市之间的风景很不错。
So that's why I like to be on trains.
所以这就是我喜欢坐火车的原因。
I actually also really enjoy taking the overnight trains because I sometimes get a little bit
其实我也很喜欢坐夜班火车，因为我有时候会觉得
uncomfortable if I travel for too long, for example, on an airplane or a car.
如果旅行时间太长，比如坐飞机或汽车，会有点不舒服。
So if I fall asleep and I wake up where I wanted to go, it's really nice.
所以如果我睡着了，醒来就到了想去的地方，那真的很棒。
Well, and I think it's nice also to be kind of rolled asleep, you know, lulled asleep
嗯，而且我觉得被火车摇着入睡也很舒服，你知道，被火车
by the train.
催眠入睡。
Have you had any like very memorable train experiences?
你有没有过什么特别难忘的火车经历？
Traveling around, I have met some interesting people and actually they, you know, local
旅行的时候，我遇到过一些有趣的人，而且他们，你知道，是当地
people.
人。
So they start talking to you and really curious because obviously you're a foreigner in their
所以他们会开始跟你聊天，而且很好奇，因为你显然是他们国家的
country and try to get to know you and maybe even give you a little bit of advice.
外国人，他们想了解你，甚至可能给你一些建议。
And if you don't speak the language, it's even a little bit more interesting because
如果你不会说他们的语言，那就更有趣了，因为
you're trying to communicate and you pick up a lot of words.
你努力沟通，还能学到很多单词。
That's true.
确实如此。
I actually heard some really interesting stories from people who took the Trans-Siberian Railway
我其实听过一些坐西伯利亚大铁路的人讲的有趣故事，
from Beijing to Moscow.
从北京到莫斯科。
They said the more vodka you drink, the more foreign languages you speak.
他们说，伏特加喝得越多，外语说得越好。
So I don't know if any of our users have done that.
所以我不知道我们的用户有没有人体验过。
You guys should let us know if you have any fun train travel experiences.
你们如果有好玩的火车旅行经历，应该告诉我们。
I know Marco certainly has some.
我知道马可肯定有一些。
I've got some of my own.
我自己也有一些。
So we'll all have to share on our website, EnglishPod.com.
所以我们都会在我们的网站 EnglishPod.com 上分享。
Right.
对。
And if you have any other questions, we'll see you guys there.
如果你们还有其他问题，我们会在那里见。
Bye.
再见。
Bye-bye for now.
暂时再见。